## STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

## software developer | user experience designer www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

relocating to Tucson, Arizona stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info 248-766-8556

## software development and UX design skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python, PHP
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Handlebars
- · Artificial intelligence
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3
- Markup languages: HTML 5
- Server environments: Node
- **Development environments:** Visual Studio
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application programming interfaces: Representational state transfer (REST), GraphQL
- UX design: wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- Digital media: Adobe Creative Cloud, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design, animation
- Prototyping: Figma
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG 2.1
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- Geocoding

### awards and grants

2014 - 2016

Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ mile
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
Miami, Florida

2014

Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ *mile* 

**Awesome Foundation** 

Boston, Massachusetts

## career objective

An award-winning software developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience creating groundbreaking web programs for organizations. Experienced in working with stakeholders to produce critically-acclaimed projects that have been featured in The New York Times, Artnet News and Detroit News. Effective at developing creative software solutions to challenging problems that help empower businesses and communities.

## professional experience

April 2021 - present

# Founding Director, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Art in Tech Services Inc

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Developed a client portal as a part of organization's website to help streamline client collaboration
- Record of 100% client satisfaction rate by effectively communicating throughout a client's project and meeting or exceeding project goals
- Created groundbreaking digital products that improve human experiences of technology by combining advancements in technology and art
- Successfully led the organization to achieve mission by investing in inhouse training in advanced technologies

April 2017 – present

## Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Public Arts Commission

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Developed key software programs to streamline operations that included a campaign application management system, an endorsement management system and a publicly searchable database of all the organization's endorsements
- Developing a voter networking and organizing portal
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art experts
- Grew Board of Directors by 233% to include leading voices in art community by delivering strong leadership
- Responsible for overall direction of the non-profit, 501(c)(4) organization

February – May 2022

# **UX Design Consultant (contract) Turnberry Solutions**

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created high-fidelity prototypes to personalize dental insurance plan shopping in the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP)
- Helped empower teams to produce great UX design for enterprise web products
- · Client: FedPoint

July 2013 – January 2017

## Web Developer and UX Designer / Co-Founding Editor ∞ mile (Infinite Mile LLC)

Detroit, Michigan

Collaborated with stakeholders to create brand and website

#### education

2009 - 2011

Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture **Yale University School of Art** 

New Haven, Connecticut

2005 - 2008

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) cum laude in Art History, Theory & Criticism **Maryland Institute College of Art** (MICA)

Baltimore, Maryland

## teaching experience

2015 - 2017

Lecturer

**University of Detroit Mercy School of Architecture Digital Media Department** Detroit, Michigan

2015 - 2016

**Special Lecturer** 

2014 - 2015

Lecturer

**Oakland University Department of Art** & Art History

Rochester, Michigan

#### websites created

• 2021 – present

Art in Tech Services Inc www.artintechservices.com

• 2017 – present

**Public Arts Commission** 

www.publicartscommission.org

• 2023

**Suzanne Conti Quilts** 

https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app

• 2022

JoyFoodly

www.joyfoodly.com

2021 – present

web work portfolio

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

 $\bullet$  2013 - 2017

∞ mile (Infinite Mile)

www.infinitemiledetroit.com

• 2008 – present

artist website

www.stephengdewyer.info

- Directed three editing staff and 78 contributors to publish 94 essays and interviews, 51 artist projects, 26 reviews and 27 works of fiction or poetry
- · Wrote successful grant applications
- Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences

### technical training

2021 - 2024

## Certificates in UX Design, Software Development and Web Accessibility,

- Beginning C++ Programming From Beginner to Beyond
- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: AI, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

2020 - 2021

### Certificates in Building Web Applications, University of Michigan -Coursera

- JavaScript, ¡Query, and JSON
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP

2021

#### Certificates in Database Design, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL

2020

### Certificates in Python Programming, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody

2020

#### **Certificates in UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation**

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- · Become a UX Designer from Scratch
- Human-Computer Interaction

2021

### Certificate in Leadership, University of Michigan - Coursera

Inspiring and Motivating Individuals

2/2